[
   {
     "qno": 1,
"question": " Simplify: 2x−3(4−x)=?",
"opa": "5x-12",
"opb": "−10+3x",
"opc": "5x−10",
"opd": "5x+12",
"correctanswer": "1"
},
   {
     "qno": 2,
"question": "In triangle ABC, angle A = 50° and angle B = 60°. What is angle C?",
"opa": "60°",
"opb": "70°",
"opc": "80°",
"opd": "90°",
"correctanswer": "2"
},
   {
     "qno": 3,
"question": "The average of five numbers is 20. If one of the numbers is 25, what is the average of the remaining four numbers?",
"opa": "18.75",
"opb": "19",
"opc": "20",
"opd": "21.25",
"correctanswer": "1"
},
   {
     "qno": 4,
"question": " A number is increased by 20% and then decreased by 20%. What is the net percentage change?",
"opa": "0%",
"opb": "4% decrease",
"opc": "4% increase",
"opd": "20% decrease",
"correctanswer": "2"
},
   {
     "qno": 5,
"question": " What is the volume of a cube of side 5 cm?",
"opa": "125 cm³",
"opb": "150 cm³",
"opc": "25 cm³",
"opd": "100 cm³",
"correctanswer": "1"
},
   {
     "qno": 6,
"question": "What is the value of 2/3 + 3/4?",
"opa": "17/12",
"opb": "5/7",
"opc": "1/2",
"opd": "11/12",
"correctanswer": "1"
},
   {
     "qno": 7,
"question": "Solve for x: 2x-3/4 = x+1/2",
"opa": "5",
"opb": "7",
"opc": "9",
"opd": "none of these",
"correctanswer": "4"
},
   {
     "qno": 8,
"question": "What is the value of 2^3 × 2^4?",
"opa": "128",
"opb": "16",
"opc": "32",
"opd": "256",
"correctanswer": "1"
},
   {
     "qno": 9,
"question": "The marks of 5 students are: 70, 65, 80, 75, 90. What is the mean?",
"opa": "75,
"opb": "76",
"opc": "78",
"opd": "72",
"correctanswer": "2"
},
   {
     "qno": 10,
"question": "Which of the following is not a rational number?",
"opa": "-3/7",
"opb": "0",
"opc": "√2",
"opd": "5/1",
"correctanswer": "√2"
}
]
